## **Brayden Babbitt**

Senior Software Engineer

#### INFORMATION

Email: <a href="mailto:brayden@babbitts.net">brayden@babbitts.net</a> Phone: (303) 856-4271

Website: braydenbabbitt.com

**LinkedIn:** <u>linkedin.com/in/brayden-babbitt</u> **GitHub:** github.com/braydenbabbitt

GitHub: github.com/hapticlabsdev

### **SKILLS**

## **Development Skills & Languages**

- React
- Typescript
- Protobuf & API schema design
- SQL/Postgres
- Python
- Go
- Flutter/Dart

#### **Digital Marketing**

- LinkedIn advertising
- Facebook/Instagram advertising
- Google Search and Display ads

#### Design

- UX & UI design (Figma, Adobe XD)
- Adobe Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, Premiere, After Effects)

**Project Management & QA** 

#### **PROJECTS**

- <u>alpha.modularmusic.net</u>: automated Spotify playlist generator (in private alpha)
  - <u>github.com/Haptic-Labs/</u> modular-music-fe
  - github.com/Haptic-Labs/ modular-music-be

#### REFERENCES

#### **Ryan Ball**

- ryanlball@gmail.com
- (385) 249-8992

### **STATEMENT**



I am one of the rare software engineers who has been on both sides of the digital marketing world. Before becoming a software engineer, I worked as a digital marketer, running digital ad campaigns, working hard on SEO, and everything else that comes with that territory. Now, as I build performant, scale-able, and user-friendly software, I benefit from being able to see the products I build from multiple perspectives: the user, the designer, and the developer, since I have been each of them myself.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

## 2022 - Present Weave Communications, Inc. Senior Software Engineer (2023 - Present)

- Lead frontend development (React SPA) to expand functionality of Weave's sms messaging inbox feature to account for more complex user stories while optimizing usage of realtime events to reduce data refetching by over 50%.
- Worked with various other feature teams to create unified user flows that integrated other features with Weave's messaging inbox that accommodated diverse needs and user contexts, and drove adoption of the same.
- Created automated codegen tools to enable all teams to connect Weave's shared protobuf schema API contracts with ReactQuery's type system, and pioneered an effort to use real-time Websocket events to drive the state of the Weave web app.
- Built robust unit testing tooling to allow for non-ui (unit) testing of ReactQuery cache updating using Vitest and React Testing Library.

#### Software Engineer (2022 - 2023)

- Migrated all preexisting functionality of the most heavily used feature of the legacy Weave app to a new codebase and modernized UI and application, while accommodating new user stories as the team's first and solo frontend engineer.
- Drove adoption of new engineering standards that set the example for other teams to scale and migrate their products as part of a complete rebuild of Weave's primary web app.

# 2021 - 2022 ZooWho, Inc. Chief Marketing Officer / Chief Technology Officer

- Managed a team of 8 developers across 3 contracting agencies to develop new features, fix bugs, and successfully roll out the Nouri personal CRM's mobile and web applications.
- Designed UI and clearly communicated UX flows to the development team to ensure attention to detail and customer expectations were met.
- Ran all SEO and digital marketing campaigns, including using various analytics tools.

#### 2020 - 2021 B2Linked Account Manager

- Created Excel VBA automations that increased efficiency of bulk ad creation using LinkedIn's advertising API by 50%.
- Optimized digital ad placements, creatives, copy, and adspend for 8 clients on LinkedIn's PPC advertising platform.
- Managed client relationships to assure timeliness, efficiency, and client satisfaction, as well as increase in adspend.

#### **EDUCATION**

2015 - 2021 Brigham Young University (BYU)

BA in Communications: Public Relations